<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/R5/fhir-single.xsd">

    <h3 id="overview">Hospital Discharge Report Overview</h3>

    <a> </a>

    <h4 id="hdr">Hospital Discharge Report</h4>

    <a> </a>

    <p>The Hospital Discharge Report (HDR) has main components:</p>
    <ul>
        <li>the header and</li>
        <li>the body.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>
The <b>header</b> contains essential administrative and identification data about the patient, healthcare providers, and other key participants in the patient's care.</p>
    <p>The <b>body</b> consists of the core clinical details regarding the patient's stay, treatment, and discharge plan.</p>

    <p>{% include hdr-mindmap.svg %}</p>

    <h4 id="header">Header</h4>

    <a> </a>

    <p>
The Hospital Discharge Report Header component provides a documentation for the:
        <ul>
            <li>
                <strong>Identification of the patient/subject:</strong> This includes critical identification information like the patient's <em>given name</em>,                <em>family name</em>,                <em>date of birth</em>, and <em>national healthcare patient ID</em>. It also covers <em>nationality</em>,                <em>gender</em>, and the patient’s <em>country of affiliation</em>.
            </li>
            <li>
                <strong>Patient/subject related contact information:</strong> This involves the patient’s <em>address</em> and <em>telecommunication contact details</em> (e.g., phone numbers and email addresses). It may also include details of a <em>preferred healthcare professional</em> (name, identifier, role, organization).</li>
            <li>
                <strong>Health insurance and payment information:</strong> Key data related to health insurance, including the <em>insurance code</em>,                <em>name of the health insurance provider</em>, and the <em>patient's health insurance number</em>.
            </li>
            <li>
                <strong>Information recipient:</strong> Refers to the intended recipient of the hospital discharge report. This includes <em>recipient's name</em>,                <em>organization</em>,                <em>address</em>, and <em>telecom details</em>.
            </li>
            <li>
                <strong>Author:</strong> Documents the <em>author of the report</em>, including their identifier (e.g., license number), name, and organizational information. The author is responsible for signing off on the content of the report.</li>
            <li>
                <strong>Attester:</strong> The healthcare professional who verifies the content of the report. This includes the <em>attester’s identifier</em>,                <em>name</em>,                <em>organization</em>, and the <em>date and time of attestation</em>.
            </li>
            <li>
                <strong>Legal authenticator:</strong> The person taking legal responsibility for the report. Includes the <em>identifier</em>,                <em>name</em>,                <em>organization</em>, and <em>date of authentication</em>.
            </li>
            <li>
                <strong>Document metadata:</strong> Contains the document's unique <em>identifier</em>,                <em>type</em>, and metadata such as the <em>date and time</em> of creation or modification, ensuring proper tracking of the report.</li>
        </ul>
    </p>


    <p>{% include header-mindmap.svg %}</p>
    <p></p>

    <h4 id="body">Body</h4>

        <a> </a>

    <p>
The Hospital Discharge Report Body component includes:
        <ul>
            <li>
                <strong>Presented form:</strong> the Hospital Discharge Report in its narrative form; that is in a printable representation.</li>
            <li>
                <strong>Advance directives:</strong> Legal documents like living wills or DNR orders guiding treatment decisions.</li>
            <li>
                <strong>Alerts:</strong> Important medical alerts like allergies or other critical patient conditions.</li>
            <li>
                <strong>Encounter:</strong> Details of the hospital encounter, including admission date, reason, and type (inpatient/outpatient).</li>
            <li>
                <strong>Admission evaluation:</strong> Key findings and diagnostic results from the admission process.</li>
            <li>
                <strong>Patient history:</strong> A comprehensive record of the patient’s medical history prior to the hospital stay.</li>
            <li>
                <strong>Course of hospitalisation:</strong> Progress of the patient during the hospital stay, including treatments and interventions.</li>
            <li>
                <strong>Discharge details:</strong> Information about the discharge date, destination, and post-discharge care instructions.</li>
            <li>
                <strong>Care plan and other recommendations after discharge:</strong> Detailed follow-up care plan, including medications and therapy recommendations.</li>
        </ul>


    </p>
    
    <p>{% include body-mindmap.svg %}</p>
    <p></p>

</div>
